An adventure so big, one dimension isn't enough.
Phineas and Ferb The Movie: Across the 2nd Dimension is a
animation, comedy, family film directed by Robert Hughes.
Phineas and Ferb get trapped in an alternate dimension where
the evil Doofenshmirtz rules the tri-state area.
They must find a way back home with the help of their pet platypus
named Perry, who they discover is a secret agent.
Phineas Flynn / Phineas-2 (voice), played by Vincent Martella.
Ferb Fletcher (voice), played by Thomas Brodie-Sangster.
Perry the Platypus / Additional Voices (voice), played by Dee Bradley Baker.
Candace Flynn / Candace-2 (voice), played by Ashley French.
Dr. Heinz Doofenshmirtz / Doof-2 / Additional Voices
(voice), played by Dan Povenmire.
Lawrence Fletcher / Lawrence-2 (voice), played by Richard O'Brien.
Phineas and Ferb the Movie: Across the 2nd Dimension is a 2011 American animated musical
science fantasy film based on the animated TV series Phineas and Ferb.
The film premiered on Disney Channel on August 5, 2011, in the United States.
It was first announced by Jeff "Swampy" Marsh during a
January 2010 interview with the Daily Telegraph.
The events of the film take place during the third season of Phineas and Ferb.
It is the first feature-length film of the Phineas and Ferb series, and the third animated Disney Channel
Original Movie, following Kim Possible Movie: So the Drama and The Proud Family Movie.
The film's premiere averaged 7.6 million viewers, making it one of the
highest-rated animated programs on cable in more than three years.
It later gained over 3 million viewers to become the second most watched animated basic cable telecast ever
among kids 6–11 and teens 9–14, and cable's fifth highest viewership movie ever in total viewers.
A standalone sequel, Phineas and Ferb the Movie: Candace Against the Universe, was
released on August 28, 2020, on Disney+, while a third film is in development.
The film explores themes of monster, sibling relationship,
one-sided love, secret agent, mad scientist.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.